<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EDA on Miguel Alvarez</title>
    <link>https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/tags/eda/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EDA on Miguel Alvarez</description>
    <generator>Source Themes academia (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; {year}</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/tags/eda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Data EDA</title>
      <link>https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/project/master_eda_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/project/master_eda_python/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northwind EDA based on SQL</title>
      <link>https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/project/northwind_eda_sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://miguelalvred.github.io/malvarez/project/northwind_eda_sql/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this project I&amp;rsquo;m going to answer different business questions based on the Northwind Database, this DB was create on PostgreSQL so, first of all, I have to connect to my local host and then launch the queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it possible I used the following libraries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandas: To store the created dataframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pandas.io.sql: To read the SQL queries into dataframes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Psycog2: To connect the notebook to the PostgreSQL engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Warnings: To make expections on warnings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Questions:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total number of clients per country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total number of orders per country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the average price per order per country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total invoice for each country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the total profit for each country?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 10 most ordered products?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 10 most expensive products?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 10 products with the highest invoice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 10 products with the highest unit profit?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the 10 most profitable products?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclussions about the Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this EDA has been carried out, a series of conclusions are drawn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The countries with the highest number of clients are USA, Germany, France and Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The countries with the highest number of orders are USA, Germany, Brazil and France.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The countries with the highest average order income are Austria, Ireland, Denmark and Germany.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The countries with the highest total income are USA, Germany, Austria and Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The countries with the highest total profit are USA, Germany, Austria and Brazil.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the information extracted about the different countries and markets, it can be corroborated that the most developed and stable markets are USA, Germany and Brazil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive product doubles the price of the previous product on the list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most expensive product, despite its high price, generates the higher income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Surprisingly, the most expensive product is also the one with the highest profit, both on a unit and overall basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to check the JupyterNotebook where I develop this project you will find it at the &lt;em&gt;Code&lt;/em&gt; button at the top of the page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
